(Live) Public Speech at UN Climate Change Conference in Bonn
(In diretta) Discorso pubblico alla Conferenza delle Nazioni Unite sul Cambiamento Climatico a Bonn (Live) Public Speech at UN Climate Change Conference in Bonn
Welcome to today's session (Moderator Dr. Xu)
Benvenuti alla sessione di oggi (Moderatore Dr. Xu) Welcome to today's session (Moderator Dr. Xu)
So on the topic of Chinese energy transition and technology innovation, we
Quindi, sul tema della transizione energetica cinese e dell'innovazione tecnologica, So on the topic of Chinese energy transition and technology innovation,
find ourselves like in the middle of an era where both the
ci troviamo nel centro di un'epoca in cui sia l'urgenza di combattere il cambiamento climatico we find ourselves like in the middle of an era where both the
urgency of combating climate change and the need for technology advancements.
che la necessità di progressi tecnologici sono urgenti. urgency of combating climate change and the need for technology advancements.
So China stands in the forefront of this challenge due to huge
La Cina è in prima linea in questa sfida a causa della sua enorme popolazione So China stands in the forefront of this challenge due to huge
population and also huge energy consumption.
e del suo enorme consumo di energia. population and also huge energy consumption.
Fast forward 10 years to today, so China has emerged as a
Facciamo un salto di 10 anni fino ad oggi, la Cina è diventata un Fast forward 10 years to today, so China has emerged as a
global leader in solar power deployment and it claimed the largest market
leader mondiale nel dispiegamento dell'energia solare e ha reclamato il mercato più grande global leader in solar power deployment and it claimed the largest market
and for the battery-powered electric vehicles.
e quello dei veicoli elettrici a batteria. and for the battery-powered electric vehicles.
So committed to a decarbonized industrial upgrades, China has recognized hydrogen as
Impegnata in un aggiornamento industriale decarbonizzato, la Cina ha riconosciuto l'idrogeno come So committed to a decarbonized industrial upgrades, China has recognized hydrogen as
an essential energy resource rather than hazardous chemicals.
una risorsa energetica essenziale piuttosto che prodotti chimici pericolosi. an essential energy resource rather than hazardous chemicals.
So this has been a significant shift that already noted in its
Questo è un cambiamento significativo che è già stato segnalato nel suo So this has been a significant shift that already noted in its
national energy law draft of 2020.
progetto di legge nazionale sull'energia del 2020. national energy law draft of 2020.
So as announced also in the latest 14th five-year development plan,
Come annunciato anche nell'ultimo piano quinquennale della 14ª edizione, So as announced also in the latest 14th five-year development plan,
China has taken extraordinary steps with substantial investment in clean hydrogen technologies
la Cina ha intrapreso passi straordinari con investimenti sostanziali in tecnologie per l'idrogeno pulito China has taken extraordinary steps with substantial investment in clean hydrogen tech
to foster a sustainable hydrogen economy and also further to achieve its
per promuovere un'economia dell'idrogeno sostenibile e, inoltre, per raggiungere il suo to foster a sustainable hydrogen economy and also further to achieve its
commitment to carbon neutrality by 2016.
impegno per la neutralità carbonica entro il 2016. commitment to carbon neutrality by 2016.
So across the continents, another chapter unfolds.
Attraverso i continenti, si sta dispiegando un altro capitolo. So across the continents, another chapter unfolds.
Europe is renowned for its long-term commitment in sustainability and tremendous
L'Europa è nota per il suo impegno a lungo termine per la sostenibilità e le sue grandi azioni Europe is renowned for its long-term commitment in sustainability and tremendous
actions in climate change.
contro il cambiamento climatico. actions in climate change.
And also Europe indeed has embraced clean energy technologies wholeheartedly since last
E l'Europa ha effettivamente adottato tecnologie di energia pulita con tutto il suo cuore sin dal secolo scorso. And also Europe indeed has embraced clean energy technologies wholeheartedly since last
century.
secolo. century.
Ambitious initiatives like European Clean Hydrogen Alliance and also the Repower EU
Iniziative ambiziose come l'Alleanza Europea per l'Idrogeno Pulito e anche il Piano Repower EU Ambitious initiatives like European Clean Hydrogen Alliance and also the Repower EU
plan are fueling innovation and fostering global collaboration.
stanno alimentando l'innovazione e promuovendo la collaborazione globale. plan are fueling innovation and fostering global collaboration.
The European Hydrogen Bank announced by the European Union in 2022 with
La Banca Europea dell'Idrogeno annunciata dall'Unione Europea nel 2022 con The European Hydrogen Bank announced by the European Union in 2022 with
an initial funding of 3 billion euros.
un finanziamento iniziale di 3 miliardi di euro. an initial funding of 3 billion euros.
So the bank aims to boost the European hydrogen market to a
La banca mira a spingere il mercato europeo dell'idrogeno a un So the bank aims to boost the European hydrogen market to a
brand new level.
nuovo livello. brand new level.
Nations like Germany, Netherlands and France, they are also making significant investment
Paesi come Germania, Paesi Bassi e Francia, stanno anche facendo investimenti significativi Nations like Germany, Netherlands and France, they are also making significant investment
in hydrogen infrastructure, pushing the boundaries of clean energy adoption.
in infrastrutture per l'idrogeno, spingendo i confini dell'adozione di energie pulite. in hydrogen infrastructure, pushing the boundaries of clean energy adoption.
Digital sustainability, the marriage of digitization and sustainability.
La sostenibilità digitale, l'unione di digitalizzazione e sostenibilità. Digital sustainability, the marriage of digitization and sustainability.
So it holds immense promise for our journey towards a sustainable future.
Offre una promessa immensa per il nostro cammino verso un futuro sostenibile. So it holds immense promise for our journey towards a sustainable future.
The power of digital sustainability, such as a rising new star, everyone
Il potere della sostenibilità digitale, come una nuova stella nascente, tutti The power of digital sustainability, such as a rising new star, everyone
knows, chatGBT, blockchain, artificial intelligence and the Internet of Things is revolutionizing
sa, chatGBT, blockchain, intelligenza artificiale e Internet delle Cose knows, chatGBT, blockchain, artificial intelligence and the Internet of Things
how we produce, distribute and consume energy.
sta rivoluzionando il modo in cui produciamo, distribuiamo e consumiamo energia. is revolutionizing how we produce, distribute and consume energy.
These technologies enable us to optimize energy systems, improve efficiency and enhance
Queste tecnologie ci permettono di ottimizzare i sistemi energetici, migliorare l'efficienza e These technologies enable us to optimize energy systems, improve efficiency and
the integration of renewable energy resources.
migliorare l'integrazione delle risorse energetiche rinnovabili. enhance the integration of renewable energy resources.
Let's imagine a world where the energy systems are smart, interconnected and
Immaginiamo un mondo in cui i sistemi energetici siano intelligenti, interconnessi e reattivi. Let's imagine a world where the energy systems are smart, interconnected and responsive.
Buildings and cities become like energy hubs, generating and sharing electricity, heat
Gli edifici e le città diventano centri energetici, generando e condividendo elettricità, calore Buildings and cities become like energy hubs, generating and sharing electricity, heat
and even hydrogen.
e anche idrogeno. and even hydrogen.
So renewable energy sources are seamlessly integrated into the grid, creating a
Le fonti di energia rinnovabile sono perfettamente integrate nella rete, creando una So renewable energy sources are seamlessly integrated into the grid, creating a
decentralized and resilient energy network.
rete energetica decentralizzata e resiliente. decentralized and resilient energy network.
By embracing clean energy technologies such as hydrogen and leveraging the power
Adottando tecnologie di energia pulita come l'idrogeno e sfruttando il potere By embracing clean energy technologies such as hydrogen and leveraging the power
of digital sustainability, we process the tools already and to drive this
della sostenibilità digitale, abbiamo già gli strumenti necessari per proseguire in questa transizione. of digital sustainability, we process the tools already and to drive this transition forward.
So governments, industrial leaders and researchers, we must collaborate on a global
I governi, i leader industriali e i ricercatori, dobbiamo collaborare su un palcoscenico globale So governments, industrial leaders and researchers, we must collaborate on a global
stage and to develop innovation solutions and forging a path towards a
e sviluppare soluzioni innovative, tracciando un cammino verso un stage and to develop innovation solutions and forging a path towards a
world powered by clean energy and driven by digital sustainability.
mondo alimentato da energia pulita e guidato dalla sostenibilità digitale. world powered by clean energy and driven by digital sustainability.
(End)
(Fine) (End)